hi i'm brett contreras the glute guy
and in this video i'm going to show you
the four main schools of thought with
how to do an exercise
now i'm going to pick the squat the
deadlift and the bench press
and there's a million different ways or
you know subtle
variations in technique but i'm going to
focus on the four main ones which are
the safest way to do an exercise the
strongest
way or the one that the way that lets
you use the most weight
the way that stresses the muscle the
most and then
the way that transfers over to your
sport the most so
here's a squat i only have 135 pounds on
here
but if you're doing a squat the safest
way is
probably you know
feet pointed relatively straight ahead
high bar
and then just go to parallel to right
there
that might be the safest way okay now
the strongest way
i'm going to shift the low bar get the
bar low on my back
i'm going to widen my stance this is how
power that there's a lift
and then i'm going to sit back
flare my feet okay that would be the
strongest way okay now the way to stress
the muscle the most
get the bar back high on my trust this
is how most bodybuilders lift they have
a really narrow stance they're trying to
work their quads the most
so they will just come come down to
about right here
keep all the tension on the quads
letting their knees travel out of it
okay and then we have the way that
transfers over to sport the most
which is different for each sport you
know if you're an olympic weightlifter
you're going to go rock bottom to here
if you're a power lifter i've already
went over that if you're a sprinter
you know maybe charlie francis used to
have his athletes just do
half squats some people believe in full
squat
but it all depends on what your sport is
okay
now let's think about
the deadlift okay in a deadlift
um safest way
would be to you know keep the whole back
arched
lift up like that okay
and the strongest way this is
debatable but a lot of guys once they
get up and wait
they really have to round their upper
back a lot
that uh shifts the uh
your though it decreases the lever arm
so the hips don't have to do as much
work
and it reduces your range of motion so
and a power lifter might keep the hips
higher so
you know one of the strongest power
lifters my dead lift like this
see my lower back is flat but my upper
back is rounded big time
or up you know the strongest way might
be
for you to go sumo just like this with a
flared stance
so maybe someone's strongest that way
all depends on the lifter
now we go with body bodybuilding
the way to stress the muscle the most
most dead most bodybuilders
do deadlifts to try and work their
hamstrings in back
so they might do rack pulls or they
might do
romanian and just keeping the hips high
focusing on getting a big stretch in the
hamstrings
and now the way that transfers to sport
the most
that's debatable but you're probably not
going to see a lot of sumo dead looking
for that you're probably
going to see mostly closer stance
probably
not let the upper back round keep it
arched
now let's go over the bench press
same thing
um
okay safest way i'm probably not gonna
have too much of an arch
i'm not gonna flare my elbows much i'm
just gonna keep it nice and
that's probably the safest way okay
if i'm trying to move the most weight
like a power lifter
i'm going to get as much arch as i can
okay i'm going to lower it low
and just flare up
okay bodybuilder trying to stress the
pecs the most
i'm actually going to go wider and
take a wider stiff and i'm going to
lower it up higher on the neck and get a
more elbows out i'm also not going to
arch much
you know mighty might even put my feet
up on the bench
maybe not but it's going to be like this
it's about here elbows out this lets me
work the pedals
and then transfer to sport you know
maybe you're alignment
and you want to stay in here so maybe i
do close grip
you know for my sport
and keep it keep it in close
so that's four ways four main ways
or four main techniques or thought
process
on how to do an exercise